SHAIKH ABDUL RAASHID



Mail:

arshaikh1917@gmail.com

Github: Repositories

(in

Linked-in: Profile



Contact: (514)-561-1591

Skilled Quality Assurance Engineer with a strong understanding in testing fundamentals, customer service skills, and a versatile skill set encompassing web development. Proficient in a wide range of testing frameworks and technologies, dedicated to enhancing software quality and user experience.

Work Experience

Concentrix January 2023 - Present

Customer Advisor: Healthcare Sector

- **Inbound Call Management:** Handling inbound calls, attentively listening to customer queries, analyzing issues, asking probing questions.
- Root Cause Identification: Determine the root cause of customer issues, aiming to address underlying problems.
- **Defect Management:** Prioritize issues, selecting appropriate defect management phase for resolution.
- **Presenting Solution:** Provide effective solutions and recommendations to customers, providing education regarding efficient product use.
- Complaint Documentation: Maintain detailed records of the customer feedback for improving product quality.
- **Performance:** Maintained a success score of 91% with average call handling time of under 14 minutes.

Navidad Infotech Pvt Ltd.

May 2019 - March 2020

Web Developer

- Web Development and Testing: Utilized technologies like HTML/CSS, Javascript, Node JS, Express, MySQL. Performed manual testing to find failures, logged defects on a comprehensive defect report. Investigated and tracked issues while performing appropriate debugging.
- User Acceptance Testing: Performed User Acceptance Testing across various products to provide feedback to enhance product quality.
- o **3D Printing:** Collaborated with semi-professional 3D printers, actively participating in maintenance activities which improved the product quality by 15%, also designed 3D models on slicing softwares.
- Product Photography: Managed equipment related to indoor photoshoot for product photography
 and conducted post processing using softwares like photoshop cc to ensure the best quality product
 images.

Education

AEC, Software Testing

September 2020 - May 2022

Cégep de la Gaspésie • Montréal

Bachelor in Technology

Computer Science & Engineering at Parul University • India

July 2015- May 2019

ErrorCollector: Github Repo

- Conducted Functional and User Acceptance Testing on various functionalities of National Geographic Website.
- Frameworks (Selenium & TestNG): Annotations such as Test({Groups}, Dependency, Priority).
- Implemented setup and teardown methods with BeforeMethod, AfterMethod, BeforeClass, AfterClass.
- Selenium classes utilized: Actions, Select, JSExecutor, Explicit/Implicit Wait.
- Handled iFrames and Window Switching when necessary.
- Developed test scripts using Java, implementing the Page Object Model and Page Factory design patterns.
- Performed testing across multiple browsers including Firefox, Chrome, Safari.
- Applied Equivalence Partitioning to structure input values, generating diverse error messages for invalid and valid inputs. Used assertions to verify the error messages.
- Future Plan: Using Maven for automated report generation to enhance project reporting capabilities.

ScotiaBank LoginTest: Github Repo

- Unit Testing: Focused on critical login functionality of ScotiaBank website, ensuring its reliability.
- **Selenium & TestNG:** Designed and executed automated tests.
- **Data Driven Testing:** To enhance test coverage, fetched variable values using Apache POI from an Excel file, allowing dynamic test data input.
- **Design Pattern:** Implemented Page Object Model and its class Page Factory, enhancing test script maintainability.
- Test Prioritization and Grouping: Set priorities on test cases, grouped test cases logically, used assertion methods for comparison of expected and actual output from the test case, ensuring the login functionality met the desired criteria.
- **Final Reports:** Generated XSLT reports using ANT.

Certifications

ISTOB Certified Tester: Foundation Level APRIL 2023

Score: 82.5% | Exam Organization: ATSQA

Networking: Cisco Certified Network Associate & Security

APRIL 2019

Score: 70% | Exam Organization: IIHT

Technologies and Languages

Programming: Java, JavaScript, SQL.

Framework: Selenium, JUnit, TestNG, Node, Vue, Bootstrap,

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, REST APIs, AJAX, jQuery, JSON, Postman, JIRA.

Software: VS Code, Eclipse GitHub, Visual Studio, IntelliJ, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Vegas Pro. Concepts: Object-Oriented Programming, Agile, SDLC, STLC, Page Object Model, TDD, BDD.

Other Experiences

Grand Burger Blvd.

October 2020 - October 2022

Ensured precision in order handling, consistently meeting timeframes and maintaining food quality per company standards. Trained new hires in cooking procedures, and order management.